http://www.iun.edu/privacy

HomeIU NorthwestPrivacy NoticeIU Northwest Privacy PolicyEffective: 2020-12-10ApplicabilityThis privacy notice applies only to the Indiana University Northwest (https://www.iun.edu/) and explains our practices concerning the collection, use, and disclosure of visitor information. Visitor information collected by Indiana University Northwest will be used only as outlined in this privacy notice.Other units at the university may collect and use visitor information in different ways. Therefore, visitors to other university websites should review the privacy notices for the particular sites they visit. Indiana University Northwest is not responsible for the content of other websites or for the privacy practices of websites outside the scope of this notice.ChangesBecause Internet technologies continue to evolve rapidly, Indiana University Northwest may make appropriate changes to this notice in the future. Any such changes will be consistent with our commitment to respecting visitor privacy, and will be clearly posted in a revised privacy notice.Collection and UsePassive/Automatic CollectionWhen you view pages on our site, the web server automatically collects certain technical information from your computer and about your connection.This site is hosted on IU Sitehosting, a shared web–hosting environment provided by IU’s University Information Technology Services. For more information about privacy practices related to IU Sitehosting, read the Webserve/IU Sitehosting Privacy Notice Supplement.In addition to any information collected by IU Sitehosting, our server and/or site collects the following:your IP addressthe domain name from which you visit our siteuser-specific information on which pages are visitedaggregate information on pages visitedthe referring websitethe date and time of visitthe duration of visityour browser typeyour screen resolutionContinued use of our website indicates consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this information as described in this notice.This technical information is retained in detail; it may not have a current retention/deletion schedule.Active/Manual/Voluntary CollectionOther than automatically collected technical information about your visit (described above, or cookies, described below), we may ask you to provide information voluntarily, such as through forms or other manual input—in order to make products and services available to you, to maintain and manage our relationship with you, including providing associated services or to better understand and serve your needs. This information is generally retained as long as you continue to maintain a relationship with us. Your providing this information is wholly voluntary. However, not providing the requested information (or subsequently asking that the data be removed) may affect our ability to deliver the products or service for which the information is needed. Providing the requested information indicates your consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this information as described in this notice. Information we may actively collect could include:the email addresses of those who communicate with us via emailthe email addresses of those who make postings to our chat areasnameaddresstelephone numberfax numberinformation volunteered by the visitor, such as preferences, survey information and/or site registrationsInformation UsageThis information is:used to customize the content of our siteused by us to contact visitors for marketing purposesAdditional Information Related to Information CollectionNot applicable.Information Used For ContactIf you supply us with your postal/mailing address:You may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events.If you do not wish to receive such mailings, or would like to be added to our "do not share" list, please let us know by:sending us an email at the listed addresscalling us at the listed telephone numberwriting to us at the listed addressClick on unsubscribe links on emailsInformation SharingWe may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information with other entities or organizations.We may share personally identifiable information with other entities or organizations, under the following circumstances:This information is:shared with agents or contractors who assist in providing support for our internal operationsshared with other reputable organizations to help them contact visitors for marketing purposesnot shared with other organizations for commercial purposesdisclosed when legally required to do so, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our website and applicable laws, or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our websiteWe may provide this information to:other Indiana University units/departments/schoolscontracted university agents/organizationsWe may make some personally identifiable information available, such as:your nameyour email addressother contact information, such as address or telephone numberExcept as provided in the Disclosure of Information section below, we do not attempt to use the technical information discussed in this section to identify individual visitors.Additional Information Related to Information UseNot applicable.CookiesA cookie is a small data file that is written to your hard drive that contains information about your visit to a web page. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may configure your browser not to accept them at all, or to notify and require approval before accepting new cookies. Some web pages/sites may not function properly if the cookies are turned off, or you may have to provide the same information each time you visit those pages.In order to customize the information and services offered to you, our site uses cookies to:store visitors preferencesrecord user-specific information on what pages users access or visitrecord past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our sitecustomize web page content on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sendsChildrenWe ask children under age 13 to obtain permission from a parent or guardian before interacting with our site.Use of Third Party ServicesThis website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies (described above) to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including possibly your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google.For more information, please visit Google’s Privacy Policy.Social MediaThird-party social media sites may collect information from this site. Indiana University is not responsible for their privacy practices. This site embeds features from third party social media sites, including:Facebook (visit Facebook's privacy policy at: https://www.facebook.com/legal/FB_Work_Privacy)Twitter (visit Twitter's privacy policy at: https://twitter.com/en/privacy)LinkedIn (visit LinkedIn's privacy policy at: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)Instagram (visit Instagram's privacy policy at: https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875)Flickr; YouTube (visit their privacy policy at: https://www.flickr.com/help/privacy; https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/#community-guidelines, https://policies.google.com/privacy)Additional Information Related to the Use of Third Party ServicesNot applicable.Access to InformationIn some cases, we will grant visitors access to the information we collect about them.This information includes:a description of information that we maintain about themUpdating Inaccurate InformationIn some cases, we will grant visitors the ability to update or correct inaccuracies in the information that we maintain.Visitors may correct inaccuracies in:contact information that we have on fileDisclosure of InformationOther than sharing your information with other appropriate university personnel and units to ensure the quality, functionality, and security of our website, or manage your relationship with us, we will not disclose personally identifiable information about your use of the site except under the following circumstances:With your prior written (including email) consentWhen we have given you clear notice that we will disclose information that you voluntarily provideWith appropriate external parties, such as law enforcement agencies, in order to investigate and respond to suspected violations of law or university policy. Any such disclosures shall comply with all applicable laws and university policies.SecurityDue to the rapidly evolving nature of information technologies, no transmission of information over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. While Indiana University is committed to protecting user privacy, IU cannot guarantee the security of any information users transmit to university sites, and users do so at their own risk.We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.Once we receive user information, we will use reasonable safeguards consistent with prevailing industry standards and commensurate with the sensitivity of the data being stored to maintain the security of that information on our systems.We will comply with all applicable federal, state and local laws regarding the privacy and security of user information.Links to non-university sitesIndiana University is not responsible for the availability, content, or privacy practices of non-university sites. Non-university sites are not bound by this site privacy notice policy and may or may not have their own privacy policies.Privacy Notice ChangesFrom time to time, we may use visitor information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice.Only data collected from the time of the policy change forward will be used for these new purposes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically.Supplemental InformationNot applicable.Contact InformationIf you have questions or concerns about this policy, please contact us.Indiana University NorthwestATTN: Office of Marketing and Communications, UITS Web Services3400 BroadwayGary, Indiana 46410marcom@iun.edu, webnw@iun.edu219-980-7116, 219-981-4357If you feel as though this site’s privacy practices differ from the information stated, you may contact us at the listed address or phone number. You may also contact 219-980-7116, 219-981-4357.If you feel that this site is not following its stated policy and communicating with the owner of this site does not resolve the matter, or if you have general questions or concerns about privacy or information technology policy at Indiana University, please contact the chief privacy officer through the University Information Policy Office, 812-855-UIPO, privacy@iu.edu.
Contact, Address, and Additional Links
Services
About
People Directory
Request IT Service
Departmental listing
Español
Library Services
trouble accessing the content on this page?
(888-968-7486)
